

## S.M. SAMEER

#### Data Engineer

Software Engineer with around 1+ years of experience in building user interactive applications, possess hands-on experience in solving syntactical challenges and scalability problems for different domains. Inclined towards the field of data engineering with a desire to expand my skill sets.

msameer112@gmail.com

B-306, BML Palms, Jamia Masjid Road, M S Palya, Vidyaranyapura Post, Bengaluru - 560097

github.com/shaikksameer

## 6362410598

in linkedin.com/in/s-m-sameer-68446b135

#### **EDUCATION**

# COMPUTER ENGINEERING AND DATA SCIENCE

PRESIDENCY UNIVERSITY, BENGALURU, KARNATAKA

08/2018 - 07/2022 7.77 CGPA

#### 12TH STANDARD

Kendriya Vidyalaya NO.1

03/2017 - 06/2018 72.06%

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Data specialist

## **Futurense Technologies**

12/2022 - Present Bangalore, Karnataka Tools Used: SQL, Python, Git, AWS Cloud, Hive, Hadoop, Databricks, Azure Achievements/Tasks

- Implemented SQL reporting on employee management system to gain insights on building various reporting formats
- Gained an overview of the whole process of **Data Engineering**
- Worked on core services in Azure Cloud under security, compute, storage, database, etc

# Conversational AI developer (Database Administrator)

#### Valenta Ai

01/2022 - 11/2022 Bangalore, Karnataka Tools Used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, OneReach.ai, Dialog Flow Achievements/Tasks

- Worked on project like creating interactive chatbot for Unicomer Group, have also deployed chatbot in various form of channels (WhatsApp, RWC, Facebook, etc)
- Enhanced several features that reduced the manual intervention by automating the process which helped to minimize the error rate by 80%
- Worked on maintaining a database containing feedback, conversations, and interests of individuals

## **SKILLS**



#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

Credit Card Analytic (03/2023 - 03/2023)

- Successfully built a complete data pipeline for analyzing credit card data using Snowflake and MongoDB and generated reports in Dashboard
- Ingested data from local to snowflake (close to 300,000 records) using snowsql and in MongoDB using mongo shell(mongoimport)
- Using SQL query in Snowflake analyzed data and mongo command in MongoDB shell
- Created reports by using the inbuilt dashboard of the snowflake and in MongoDB exported (mongoexport) the solution in the format of CSV file and used Power BI for building dashboard

# PlayerTracker: Building a Comprehensive Database for Tracking Player (09/2020 - 10/2020)

- Created a python-interface, with a menu-driven to automate the process of admin users
- Collected and stored the duration using MySQL database and built 3 triggers to streamline the process inserting data, and trigger to make decision on the subscription status
- Worked on Visualization palette to show the usage of the package and total hours played by the user using Matplotlib

#### HealthCare Management (06/2022 - 07/2022)

- Developed over 15+ stored routines with features such as obtaining pharmacy information for particular medications, determining the count of patients treated for specific diseases in a given city and etc
- Utilized SQL Joins , Aggregate Functions , and Window Functions to extract meaningful insights from the data
- Constructed 3 triggers to monitor and store the date and time of when a new city or state is added to the database, and to track all transactions that involve updating inventory

#### **CERTIFICATES**

Supervised Learning with scikit-learn (06/2020 - 07/2020)

Data Camp

Applied Plotting, Charting & Data Representation in Python (07/2020 - 08/2020)

coursera.org /verif y/YKG BBKH G C BM W